<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on drew dot shoes</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on drew dot shoes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 22:45:42 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drew.shoes/posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Watch Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/how-to-watch-mission-impossible-dead-reckoning-part-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 22:45:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://drew.shoes/posts/how-to-watch-mission-impossible-dead-reckoning-part-one/</guid><description>After this summer&amp;rsquo;s blockbuster release of Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One, you might find yourself wondering: Can I stream Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One? Where can I watch Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One online? Is Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One available for rent or video on demand? How Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One watch now go please?
Well, wonder no more.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After this summer&rsquo;s blockbuster release of <strong>Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One</strong>, you might find yourself wondering: Can I stream <strong>Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One</strong>? Where can I watch <strong>Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One</strong> online? Is <strong>Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One</strong> available for rent or video on demand? How <strong>Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One</strong> watch now go please?</p>
<p>Well, wonder no more. The latest installment of the Mission: Impossible franchise, <strong>Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One</strong>, is now available to watch at home! The Tom Cruise film is currently available to purchase on demand for $19.99 on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/video/detail/amzn1.dv.gti.223c23ef-bfb4-4281-90a7-41053fa9db7e" target="_blank" rel="noopener" ><strong>Amazon Prime Video</strong></a>, <a href="https://tv.apple.com/us/movie/mission-impossible---dead-reckoning-part-one/umc.cmc.3z4wfslwhuf77i0tgk7q3yt41" target="_blank" rel="noopener" ><strong>Apple TV</strong></a>, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/movies/details/Mission_Impossible_Dead_Reckoning_Part_One" target="_blank" rel="noopener" ><strong>Google Play</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.vudu.com/content/browse/details/Mission-Impossible-Dead-Reckoning-Part-One/2489354" target="_blank" rel="noopener" ><strong>Vudu</strong></a>, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yVgSY3XvTdA" target="_blank" rel="noopener" ><strong>YouTube</strong></a>. It is not currently available to rent. The Blu-Ray release will be on October 31st, and at some later date <strong>Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One</strong> will be available to stream on <strong>Paramount+</strong>. It is also available for free on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent" target="_blank" rel="noopener" ><strong>BitTorrent</strong></a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usenet_newsgroup" target="_blank" rel="noopener" ><strong>Usenet newsgroups</strong></a>.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/avz06PDqDbM" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<hr>
<p>OK, now that I&rsquo;ve got that SEO out of the way, I&rsquo;d like to instead talk about how to <em>prepare</em> to watch <strong>Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One</strong>, organized by how much time you&rsquo;re willing to devote.</p>
<h1 id="no-time">No Time</h1>
<p>Just go watch the movie, you&rsquo;ll be able to follow and enjoy it just fine. See it on the biggest screen with the best sound you can.</p>
<h1 id="a-few-minutes">A Few Minutes</h1>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what you need to know, assuming no prior knowledge.</p>
<ul>
<li>These are spy movies about an American intelligence agency called the IMF (Impossible Missions Force), doing missions that are impossible.</li>
<li>But these movies actually revolve around Tom Cruise&rsquo;s character, Ethan Hunt.</li>
<li>Tom Cruise does his own stunts, so every action scene you see him do is pretty much exactly what&rsquo;s actually happening, and that&rsquo;s the fun of it. When he&rsquo;s riding a motorcycle with no helmet, it&rsquo;s because the movie wants you to see that it&rsquo;s Tom Cruise, and if he was wearing a helmet you&rsquo;d just assume it was a stunt double.</li>
<li>Spies in Mission: Impossible have the ability to wear masks that make them look like anyone else as well as mimic their voices. The best moment in any Mission: Impossible movie is when someone peels off the mask, it&rsquo;s akin to using NOS in the Fast &amp; Furious movies. A running gag in the later movies is that the mask printing machine frequently breaks and the team will have to scramble.</li>
<li>Other top Mission: Impossible tropes: Tom Cruise&rsquo;s character going rogue, being assigned a mission via some form of tape that self destructs after playing, Tom Cruise sprinting long distances.</li>
<li>Over time, the series has evolved so that the most important thing in the main characters&rsquo; lives is their friends. It&rsquo;s almost identical to the emphasis on family in the Fast &amp; Furious movies.</li>
<li>If I had to briefly describe Tom Cruise&rsquo;s character, Ethan Hunt, in my own words: There is no secret he cannot extract, no security he cannot breach, no person he cannot become. He has most likely anticipated this very conversation and is waiting to strike in whatever direction we move. Sir, Hunt is the living manifestation of destiny - and he has made you his mission.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="many-hours">Many Hours</h1>
<p>Your best bet is to simply rewatch the other Mission: Impossible movies, all streaming on Paramount+ and BitTorrent. The movies are: 1, 2, 3, Ghost Protocol, Rogue Nation, and Fallout. Ideally, watch all of them in order. The only one that&rsquo;s pretty objectively bad is 2 (although it&rsquo;s a very fun silly watch), but 2 and 3 are the ones to skip. If you can only watch a few and just want to be able to understand what&rsquo;s going on in Mission: Impossible — Dead Reckoning Part One, I&rsquo;d watch Fallout and 1. But the best action scene in any of the movies is in Ghost Protocol.</p>
<h1 id="too-much-time">Too Much Time</h1>
<p>I really like the <a href="https://www.blankcheckpod.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Blank Check podcast</a>, and they&rsquo;ve covered all of the Mission: Impossible movies. Their <a href="https://soundcloud.com/griffin-and-david-present/mission-impossible-ghost-protocol" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Ghost Protocol episode</a> is available for free, and they later did <a href="https://blank-check.fandom.com/wiki/Mission:_Impossible" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >commentary episodes</a> of every single movie on their <a href="https://www.patreon.com/blankcheck/posts" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Patreon feed</a>. These episodes are really fun and provide a lot of great context and information about the making of these movies. For a quick taste you can also read host David Sims&rsquo; article <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2015/07/tom-cruise-mission-impossible-rogue-nation/399935/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >What Mission: Impossible Understands About Tom Cruise</a>.</p>
<p>As mentioned frequently on the Blank Check episodes, the director of the last several Mission: Impossible films, Chris McQuarrie, has some incredible in-depth interviews on the <a href="https://www.empireonline.com/podcasts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Empire Film Podcast</a> covering Rogue Nation and Fallout. Those old episodes are now behind a paywall, but you can find <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Mission_Impossible/comments/hac0vm/empire_podcast_interviews/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >links to them on Reddit</a>. I was shocked by how much I enjoyed listening to Chris McQuarrie talk about his process on these movies. He doesn&rsquo;t sound like any other director I&rsquo;ve heard in interviews. His big break in the film industry was writing The Usual Suspects, which won him an Oscar. After that he spent years as a &ldquo;script doctor&rdquo;, doing uncredited rewrites for movies like Batman &amp; Robin and X-Men. He started working with Tom Cruise after writing Valkyrie, and they&rsquo;ve since become inseparable. He works really well with Tom Cruise and they both really get how to play to his strengths. Chris McQuarrie doesn&rsquo;t believe in auteur theory, swears by test screenings as part of his process, and has a very healthy understanding for how little an audience is paying attention. He enjoys making intricate spy plots in Mission: Impossible movies, but also understands that most viewers won&rsquo;t be paying enough attention so he makes sure that you can follow his movies without sweating the details. There&rsquo;s a lot more that surprised me about the way he works, but it&rsquo;s better to hear him talk about it on these episodes.</p>
<h1 id="way-too-much-time">Way Too Much Time</h1>
<p>If you&rsquo;ve done all of the above and still would like more, you should check out the <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Light The Fuse podcast</a>. Light The Fuse has been releasing weekly episodes since 2018, with a simple premise: interview anyone they can find who has worked on any Mission: Impossible movie. This includes actors, directors, editors, but also stunt doubles, makeup artists, visual effects artists, and even a marketing intern. The interviews are definitely not hard-hitting since many of the subjects are still active in their careers and the hosts of the show are super fans, but the secret sauce of each episode is that every single guest has at least one good Tom Cruise story from working on these movies. Still, I&rsquo;d recommend listening to these at 2X speed or so since the guests aren&rsquo;t usually used to being interviewed and things can move a little slowly.</p>
<p>This year, Light The Fuse was declared the official podcast of Mission: Impossible, and has gotten to go to red carpet premieres and given more direct access to the cast and crew for interviews. Unfortunately, that also means the 238 episodes recorded beforehand are no longer available on their main feed, and are instead only able to be streamed from <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/episode-guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >their site</a>. This is a bummer, but it does make sense that Paramount wouldn&rsquo;t want to mark these older episodes as &ldquo;official&rdquo;, since they can occassionally say negative things about the movies. Fortunately for you, I&rsquo;ve gone rogue and scraped their site to generate a <a href="https://drew.shoes/misc/lightTheRogueFuse.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Light the Fuse: Rogue Backlog Feed</a>. Your mission, should you choose to accept it, is to pick a few episodes that sound interesting to you and jump in! Here are a few that I enjoyed:</p>
<ul>
<li>Director Christopher McQuarrie on episodes <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/28-christopher-mcquarrie-interview-part-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >28</a> and <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/29-christopher-mcquarrie-interview-part-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >29</a>.</li>
<li>Brad Bird, director of Ghost Protocol, on episodes <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/39-brad-bird-interview-part-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >39</a> <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/40-brad-bird-interview-part-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >40</a> and <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/41-brad-bird-interview-part-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >41</a>.</li>
<li>Barney Burman, Makeup Artist, on episodes <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/47-barney-burman-interview-part-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >47</a> and <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/48-barney-burman-interview-part-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >48</a>. Him talking about how they make the Mission: Impossible masks was fascinating.</li>
<li>Keith Campbell, Tom Cruise&rsquo;s stunt double, on episodes <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/70-keith-campbell-interview-part-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >70</a> <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/71-keith-campbell-interview-part-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >71</a> and <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/72-keith-campbell-interview-part-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >72</a>. A funny wrinkle to this is that Keith Campbell made a career out of being Tom Cruise&rsquo;s stunt double, until Tom Cruise decided to always do his own stunts and never needed him again.</li>
<li>Stu Maschwitz, Digital Effects Artist for Mission: Impossible, on episodes <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/64-stu-maschwitz-interview-part-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >64</a> <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/65-stu-maschwitz-interview-part-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >65</a> and <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/66-stu-maschwitz-interview-part-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >66</a>. I loved hearing Stu talk about the challenges of doing digital effects for a movie in 1996.</li>
<li>Todd Vaziri, Digital Effects Artist for Mission: Impossible III and Ghost Protocol, on episodes <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/67-todd-vaziri-interview-part-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >67</a> and <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/68-todd-vaziri-interview-part-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >68</a>.</li>
<li>Craig O&rsquo;Brien, Skydiving Camera Operator for Fallout, on episode <a href="https://www.lightthefusepodcast.com/166-craig-obrien-interview" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >166</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>As Tom would say: We&rsquo;ll see you at the movies!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unordered List 07-11-2023</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/ul-07-11-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 22:35:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://drew.shoes/posts/ul-07-11-2023/</guid><description>Did I haven&amp;rsquo;t made one of these posts since March. That&amp;rsquo;s mostly because we had our first child in May! So it&amp;rsquo;s been quite hectic. Everyone is healthy and happy and we are loving getting to know our little one. I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting links to post since last time, so some of these are going to be a little stale, sorry!
Read How the New York Times Managed to Avoid Ruining Wordle.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="did">Did</h1>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t made one of these posts since March. That&rsquo;s mostly because we had our first child in May! So it&rsquo;s been quite hectic. Everyone is healthy and happy and we are loving getting to know our little one. I&rsquo;ve been collecting links to post since last time, so some of these are going to be a little stale, sorry!</p>
<h1 id="read">Read</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/03/how-the-new-york-times-managed-to-avoid-ruining-wordle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >How the New York Times Managed to Avoid Ruining Wordle</a>. In a world where anything fun online is being actively ruined by business interests, I enjoyed this writeup of how Wordle wasn&rsquo;t ruined by the NYT.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.polygon.com/23655445/john-wick-4-top-down-one-shot-fight-hong-kong-massacre" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >John Wick 4’s director and crew walk us through its stunning one-shot fight</a>. This was by far my favorite scene in John Wick 4, and I loved this breakdown discussing it.</li>
<li><a href="https://kotaku.com/candy-crush-competition-all-stars-2023-prizes-finals-1850353139?rev=1681923261797" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Candy Crush Mom Accidentally Entered $250k Tournament, Kills It</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.theringer.com/movies/2023/4/14/23682450/my-neighbor-totoro-anniversary-hayao-miyazaki" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Thirty-Five Years Later, There’s Nothing Like ‘My Neighbor Totoro’</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ew.com/tv/susan-harris-golden-girls-soap-oral-history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Oral History of Susan Harris, Creator of Golden Girls</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/opinion/openforum/article/sfusd-teacher-payroll-san-francisco-bureaucracy-18000777.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >64 software bugs, complex union rules and a $15.8 million mistake: Why S.F. can’t pay its teachers on time</a>. an incredible technical breakdown of what went so horribly wrong with the San Francisco Unified Schools payroll system.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thewrap.com/its-always-sunny-in-philadelphia-wordiest-tv-show/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >‘It’s Always Sunny in Philadelphia’ Has the Most Words Per Minute of Any TV Show</a>. They never say the words have to be smart.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.gq.com/story/ryan-gosling-summer-2023-cover-profile-ken-barbie" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Ryan Gosling GQ Profile promoting Barbie</a>. There&rsquo;s an overwhelming amount of press around the upcoming Barbie movie, but I really enjoyed the photo shoot and the interview here. On people saying he was too old to play Ken:</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>But suddenly, it’s like, ‘No, we’ve cared about Ken this whole time.’ No, you didn’t. You never did. You never cared. Barbie never fucked with Ken. That’s the point. If you ever really cared about Ken, you would know that nobody cared about Ken. So your hypocrisy is exposed. This is why his story must be told.</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/money/23733244/bullshit-jobs-work-employment-lazy-jobless-employed-nothing-to-do" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >How some people get away with doing nothing at work</a>. I really enjoyed some small details of this piece that I hadn&rsquo;t seen elsewhere of people coping with having their job mostly disappear without anyone noticing, like consciously having to keep up your skillset on the side, and being afraid to make any moves or changes internally lest you get noticed and immediately laid off instead.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="san-franciscobay-area">San Francisco/Bay Area</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;m making this its own subsection because there have been a lot of breathless fear-mongering discussions about the San Francisco death spiral, doom loop, etc. I love living in San Francisco, it has its fair share of problems, but the national media (and local newspaper the Chronicle) depictions of San Francisco don&rsquo;t really represent the city I live in and love. So I&rsquo;m going to regularly post links to positive things about this city.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://sfist.com/2023/06/26/sf-chronicle-now-seems-to-regret-amplifying-the-doom-loop-narrative-it-heavily-amplified/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >SF Chronicle Now Seems to Regret Amplifying the &lsquo;Doom Loop&rsquo; Narrative It Heavily Amplified</a></li>
<li><a href="https://bookmaniac.org/2023/03/31/pet-peeve-about-local-tourist-advice/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Great SF Tourist Advice for Elderly or People with Limited Mobility</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/oursf/article/san-francisco-nordstrom-18086878.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >The San Francisco Nordstrom is closing. It was also a wild success</a></li>
<li><a href="https://brokeassstuart.com/2023/05/31/the-character-assassination-of-san-francisco/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >The Character Assassination of San Francisco</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/sf/bayarea/heatherknight/article/landmark-light-shows-18140160.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Laser light shows are coming to some of San Francisco&rsquo;s biggest landmarks</a>. These have been really fun, the header image of Sutro Tower is from this.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="social-media-discussions">Social Media Discussions</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s mostly been an exhausting and tedious navel-gazey discussion, but here are some pieces that I enjoyed:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://erinkissane.com/blue-skies-over-mastodon" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Erin Kissane&rsquo;s thoughtful piece on Mastodon</a></li>
<li><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/06/op-ed-why-the-great-twittermigration-didnt-quite-pan-out/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Why the great #TwitterMigration didn’t quite pan out</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/7/3/23782607/social-web-public-apps-end-reddit-twitter-mastodon" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Reddit, Twitter, Mastodon: where are we all supposed to go now?</a></li>
</ul>
<h1 id="watched">Watched</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>April 1st <a href="https://youtu.be/zhCjz6Gljtg" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >SNL Weekend Update</a>. The reason it&rsquo;s funny has nothing to do with the title of the video.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zhCjz6Gljtg" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/6zu7XNpppYk" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Rushmore Academy and the Max Fischer Players at the 1999 MTV Movie Awards</a>. How had I never seen this before?! The kids from Rushmore parodying other movies from 1999.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6zu7XNpppYk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wQU5vU5ENwo" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >The Giant&rsquo;s Dream: The Making of the Iron Giant</a>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wQU5vU5ENwo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In TV,</p>
<ul>
<li>We finished the most recent season of <strong>Survivor</strong>, which was excellent, and my partner won $200 in our fantasy Survivor league. Congrats to her!</li>
<li>I watched <strong>Jury Duty</strong> and thought it was just ok. The final episode after the reveal was very wholesome and fun, but I think the absurdity of <strong>Nathan For You</strong> and <strong>How To With John Wilson</strong> and similar shows made the hijinks in this one feel tamer by comparison.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>In Movies, you can see everything in <a href="https://letterboxd.com/dtschust/films/diary/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >my letterboxd</a> but here are some standouts.</p>
<ul>
<li>I rewatched all of the <strong>Mission Impossible</strong> movies leading up to watching <strong>Dead Reckoning</strong> in IMAX at a fan event on Monday with my friend Brook. We had a great time at the movies, just like Tom wanted!</li>
<li><strong>Too Funny to Fail: The Life &amp; Death of The Dana Carvey Show</strong>: A very fun watch, everyone involved has gone on to be so successful that they aren&rsquo;t bitter about the show&rsquo;s failure and can be very honest about the decisions that they made that doomed it.</li>
<li><strong>Fast X</strong> was bad, but I expected it to be and still love the franchise, no hard feelings. Momoa was great in it though.</li>
<li><strong>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Honor Among Thieves</strong> was an uplifting and fun delight.</li>
<li><strong>BlackBerry</strong> and <strong>Air</strong> were solid movies about business.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="played">Played</h1>
<ul>
<li>I purchased a bunch of games from the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Steam Summer Sale</a> but haven&rsquo;t really gotten to play any of them yet.</li>
<li>I did install and start playing <a href="https://gamejolt.com/games/sonictripletrouble16bit/322794" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >a fan made Sonic game</a> on my Steam Deck, it seems really ambitious and in the brief amount of time I&rsquo;ve played it I&rsquo;ve really enjoyed it! <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SteamDeck/comments/wh4mjg/this_sonic_remake_is_great_on_deck/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Here are some instructions on getting it to work on the Steam Deck.</a></li>
</ul>
<h1 id="computered">Computered</h1>
<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;m still really enjoying <a href="https://arc.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Arc Browser</a>, and think <a href="https://tidbits.com/2023/05/01/arc-will-change-the-way-you-work-on-the-web/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >this writeup</a> is a great intro.</li>
<li>Subscribe to your Mastodon bookmarks as an RSS Feed with <a href="https://bookmark-rss.services.woodland.cafe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >this free tool</a>. You gotta love the open web. I have a similar workflow in place that uses Pinboard instead and follows my Pinboard RSS feed, but if I didn&rsquo;t have that set up already I&rsquo;d definitely check this out.</li>
</ul>
<p>ok, bye.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unordered List 03-19-2023</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/ul-03-19-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 14:06:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://drew.shoes/posts/ul-03-19-2023/</guid><description>Did Nothing super interesting to report. I went in to the office 4 days this week, a rarity since the pandemic. It felt pretty tiring by the end, but I was reminded that I used to go in 5 days a week every week, so I think I&amp;rsquo;ll readjust pretty quickly. I continue to enjoy going into the office to have some separation between work and home, and it&amp;rsquo;s been really nice to see my coworkers that come into the office as well.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="did">Did</h1>
<p>Nothing super interesting to report. I went in to the office 4 days this week, a rarity since the pandemic. It felt pretty tiring by the end, but I was reminded that I used to go in 5 days a week <em>every week</em>, so I think I&rsquo;ll readjust pretty quickly. I continue to enjoy going into the office to have some separation between work and home, and it&rsquo;s been really nice to see my coworkers that come into the office as well. I love a routine, and there&rsquo;s been a lot of changes to my work environment recently so it&rsquo;s been fun establishing new ones.</p>
<p>The California Poppies are in full bloom all over Twin Peaks, so I went up with a coffee on Saturday morning to enjoy the spring energy and clear weather while it still lasts. This morning I awoke to rain, and rushed out to meet it head on with a much chillier and wetter walk to twin peaks. Just as invigorating though! It&rsquo;s nice to see the chronicle is on board with my assertion last week that the only cure for this weather is <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/bayarea/nativeson/article/cabin-fever-virus-no-vaccination-fight-17844628.php#photo-23584218" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >a nice little walk</a>.</p>
<h1 id="read">Read</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I&rsquo;m currently reading Jenny Odell&rsquo;s <a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/how-to-do-nothing-resisting-the-attention-economy-jenny-odell/8076119" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >How to Do Nothing</a>. I picked it up years ago and got most of the way through it and really enjoyed it, but never ended up finishing it. It hits very differently in a Covid world and with a little bit of distance from the Trump presidency.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been absolutely loving the <a href="https://brr.fyi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >brr blog</a>, dispatches from a person from San Francisco who is spending about a year doing IT work in Antarctica. Each post is a little slice of life of what it&rsquo;s like to live in Antarctica. My favorite posts so far are the ones about <a href="https://brr.fyi/posts/doors-of-mcmurdo" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >doors</a>, <a href="https://brr.fyi/posts/showering-at-the-south-pole" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >showering</a> and <a href="https://brr.fyi/posts/frost" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >frost</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Absolutely my shit: <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/sf/bayarea/heatherknight/article/bay-lights-bridge-led-17841992.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >S.F.’s ‘Bay Lights’ refused to go dark. It took a ‘Mission Impossible’ to literally pull the plug</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://washpost.engineering/heres-how-the-washington-post-verified-its-journalists-on-mastodon-7b5dbc96985c" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Here’s how The Washington Post verified its journalists on Mastodon</a>. I clicked this article assuming it would be a quick explanation of how <a href="https://docs.joinmastodon.org/user/profile/#verification" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Mastodon verifies links</a>, but this was a more involved process than I expected, and was a fun read.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>This guy has decided to <a href="https://sfba.social/@danc/110024663231452130" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >visit every park in San Francisco</a>, and I&rsquo;m going to enjoy following along!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>My buddy Paul Russo at Akita Software <a href="https://www.akitasoftware.com/blog-posts/we-built-an-exceedingly-polite-ai-dog-that-answers-questions-about-your-apis" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >built an Exceedingly Polite AI Dog That Answers Questions About Your APIs</a>. Love this!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Hell yeah, <a href="https://deadline.com/2023/03/peacock-orders-monk-movie-tony-shalhoub-original-series-cast-1235300773/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Monk&rsquo;s coming back</a>. I cannot wait to see how Monk handled the pandemic.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Soleil Ho wrote about their experiment trying to live off <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/opinion/article/california-snap-calfresh-food-assistance-hunger-17829788.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >food stamps for a week</a> (big deal, <a href="https://preview.redd.it/when-someone-tries-to-educate-me-on-the-complexities-and-v0-agldgxmfgij91.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=f5e185f983854fe338b97fcd98b8a5fc73415ea2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >I lived in Egypt for a month!</a>). These sorts of articles are usually really cringey and out of touch (wow, poor people can&rsquo;t buy organic avocados?!), but Soleil avoids all of that and leverages their chef expertise as well as previous experiences living off food stamps to write something really compelling.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="watched">Watched</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I&rsquo;m a huge fan of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@KRAZAM" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Krazam</a> videos. I think their most recent, presented live on stage at a tech conference, is their most ambitious one yet, and their most successful. In an industry with possibly the worst collective sense of humor imaginable, we are blessed with a Krazam that we do not deserve.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NAkAMDeo_NM" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>My alma mater Purdue University entered the NCAA tournament this weekend as the number 1 seed in their bracket. This was preceded by <a href="https://theathletic.com/4298487/2023/03/11/purdue-zach-edey-big-ten-tournament/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >many</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/03/17/sports/ncaabasketball/zach-edey-purdue.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >breathless</a> articles about the uniqueness of their situation, having built their entire team around a 7-foot-4 305 pound center whose singular weakness, as far as I can tell, is that he simply is not good at basketball. Purdue has never failed to disappoint me over the years, so I was delighted to watch the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/03/17/sports/ncaabasketball/fairleigh-dickinson-purdue-upset.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >team absolutely crumble</a> in the very first game, becoming only the second #1 seed ever to lose to a #16 seed in the first round. Yesterday I got a little more of my schadenfreude fix with this <a href="https://theathletic.com/4323873/2023/03/18/fairleigh-dickinson-purdue-cbs-ncaa-tournament/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >detailed writeup</a> of what it was like to work the broadcast for such a historic game. Also, be sure to check out photos of their demented mascot <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Purdue_Pete" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Purdue Pete</a> throughout history.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I saw the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fOj0lRfKiVE" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >trailer for the Blackberry movie</a> and refuse to believe that that&rsquo;s the actual tone of the movie. With that cast and that premise, it <em>has</em> to be a parody. But we do live in an era of Ben Affleck <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FOhhGFCsGrY" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >directing a film</a> about the white guys at Nike who dared to ask Michael Jordan to wear their shoe, so I don&rsquo;t know what to think anymore. Instead of embedding either of those videos, please enjoy this incredible old sketch from the writer, director, and one of the stars of the Blackberry movie.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B_qnI1WrlnU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Actors Roundtable with Justin Theroux, Rajat Suresh, Jeremy Levick &amp; More. I haven&rsquo;t made it all the way through this, but it&rsquo;s really an incredible piece of media. Props to Justin Theroux for being so game in this, although it&rsquo;s not as surprising if you know that he co-wrote Tropic Thunder.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uhvEr8OCtfI" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Back to the Blackberry movie, I think Glenn Howerton&rsquo;s Always Sunny colleague Rob McElhenney said everything that needed to be said on the issue:
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/oCEFSiAHbr">pic.twitter.com/oCEFSiAHbr</a></p>&mdash; Rob McElhenney (@RMcElhenney) <a href="https://twitter.com/RMcElhenney/status/1628213348318978048?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 22, 2023</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In Movies, I finally got around to watching <em>Won’t You Be My Neighbor?</em> and really enjoyed that. I watched the trailer for the one where Tom Hanks plays Mr. Rogers but think I got what I was looking for from the documentary.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Also, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23641849/pitch-black-chronicles-of-riddick-trilogy-netflix-sci-fi" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >The Riddick Trilogy is currently streaming on Netflix</a>. I don&rsquo;t know that I&rsquo;d recommend them, but watching them sure is a trip.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Like most of us, I&rsquo;ve been watching a lot of clips of Lance Reddick after his untimely passing this week. My favorite so far was this anecdote and corresponding video about his appearance on the Eric Andre Show. I&rsquo;d also really like to know more about his <a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/JordanVanDina/status/1636810877214289920" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >on-stage depiction of Roman</a> performing a fake script called <em>Fast Nein: The Fast and the Fuhrer</em>.
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I read on a clickbait site that Lance Reddick didnt know the show,did reserch,was confused  but dug it. <br><br>But wrote he own ideas for his bit. So very little of this skit was eric andre&#39;s ideas lol <br><br>(yes eric legit did get scared by the table thing) <a href="https://t.co/ua96bG3vGe">https://t.co/ua96bG3vGe</a> <a href="https://t.co/dkdpTbJaJr">pic.twitter.com/dkdpTbJaJr</a></p>&mdash; Y2K virus victim 🇿🇦 (@ProjectAuuman) <a href="https://twitter.com/ProjectAuuman/status/1637095696544169985?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 18, 2023</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="played">Played</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t played anything new, but did pick up a couple of games from the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/593110/view/3694679839286985808" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Steam Spring Sale</a>: Red Dead Redemption 2, Dead Cells, and No Man&rsquo;s Sky. If my current Steam collection is any indication, I will never play any of these games. I&rsquo;ve had Bioshock at the &ldquo;top of my queue&rdquo; since 2007 and still haven&rsquo;t played it, despite purchasing it at least 4 times.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been playing <a href="https://www.fantasysurvivorgame.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Fantasy Survivor</a> this season, and have been in first place in my league for the last two weeks. I&rsquo;m getting in my gloating now as I&rsquo;m sure I will fall off my perch very soon. The web site for this is incredibly confusing to navigate, the rules are too complicated, and it&rsquo;s easy to forget to vote every single week. I thrive in the chaos.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="computered">Computered</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://sindresorhus.com/velja" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Velja</a> is a really great free utility that I&rsquo;ve added to my setup recently. You set it to be your default browser, and then you can configure it to open different URL patterns in different applications. I don&rsquo;t use it for much, but the built-in Zoom functionality means that Zoom links open directly in Zoom instead of littering my browser with useless zoom tabs that I need to clean up. There&rsquo;s also a great option to strip tracking parameters out of links, but I have that disabled for web development reasons. Shoutout to the Velja developer for a dedicated part of the FAQ to explain why <a href="https://sindresorhus.com/velja#slack" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >this can&rsquo;t &ldquo;just work&rdquo; for Slack</a>. A top-tier free &ldquo;set it and forget it&rdquo; application.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://one-sec.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >One Sec App</a>. I recently tried out One Sec for about a week, it&rsquo;s sort of a souped up version of iOS&rsquo;s existing Screen Time functionality. It&rsquo;s got some great ideas, for example I really like the choices of different animations when you need to take a break before using an application. Taking a single slow deep breath is always helpful and restorative, yet I almost never think to do it. Ultimately I stopped using the app because the implementation method was sort of flakey and a pain to set up (everything is done using iOS shortcuts, which you must painfully set up manually for each app you want to limit your time on). This is Apple&rsquo;s fault for limitations around its APIs, not the creators of One Sec. Personally I&rsquo;m hoping that Apple Sherlocks them and builds most of this functionality directly into Screen Time itself.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>ok, bye.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Moving the Posts: Adventures in Legacy Infrastructure Migrations</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/moving-the-posts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 21:50:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://drew.shoes/posts/moving-the-posts/</guid><description>I figured I&amp;rsquo;d mix things up a little bit and write a post that has nothing to do with computers or software development.
At my previous apartment in the Richmond neighborhood of San Francisco, there was a utility pole right outside my apartment that was a real eyesore. My pole wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly special, most utility poles in the neighborhood looked like this: wires snaking out in every direction, across the street, tangling through trees, etc.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I figured I&rsquo;d mix things up a little bit and write a post that has nothing to do with computers or software development.</p>
<p>At my previous apartment in the Richmond neighborhood of San Francisco, there was a utility pole right outside my apartment that was a real eyesore. My pole wasn&rsquo;t particularly special, most utility poles in the neighborhood looked like this: wires snaking out in every direction, across the street, tangling through trees, etc. On windy days, two wires that appeared to have simply been cut instead of removed would loudly bang against my windows. On a day without fog (rare), the wires obstructed my very narrow view of the Golden Gate Bridge.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t know enough about how any of this works to know <em>why</em> this utility pole might have been in need of some maintenance, but it certainly didn&rsquo;t give a ton of confidence even at a glance by a layman like myself. Regardless, the company in charge of this pole, <a href="https://www.pge.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >PG&amp;E</a>, did invest in some maintenance last year, and I&rsquo;d like to imagine what might have happened.</p>
<h1 id="the-proposal">The Proposal</h1>
<p>Let&rsquo;s pretend you are the infrastructure engineer at PG&amp;E who is in charge of this pole. You&rsquo;ve been watching more and more wires get added to this pole over the years, each one increasing the complexity and overall risk of the system. Finally, some change or decay in the system crossed a risk threshold where you now felt the need to advocate for maintenance and improvements. You write a proposal and share it with leadership. The proposal has all the usual things:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Describing the problem and its impact</strong>: You break down what&rsquo;s wrong with the current implementation of this pole, and the risks to the business of not addressing them.</li>
<li><strong>Definition of Done</strong>: You outline what a successful migration is. In this case, a successful migration would be that the new pole is installed, the wires have been attached to it, and the system is still operating smoothly.</li>
<li><strong>The Proposal</strong>: You define the phases and milestones of the project. Obviously there&rsquo;s more detail, but these would be the basic steps:
<ul>
<li>Install a new utility pole next to the existing one.</li>
<li>Migrate existing wires to the new pole.</li>
<li>Refactor the system (either during the migration or afterwards, whichever makes the most sense) to clean up the technical debt that&rsquo;s accumulated over time.</li>
<li>Verify that the migration has been a success.</li>
<li>Remove the old utility pole.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>These sorts of proposals get written at your company all the time, and most of them never get prioritized. For some reason, either due to the quality of your proposal, the potential risk of not fixing the pole, or just sheer luck and timing, your project gets funded! Your manager tells you this project is going to have really high visibility, and that if you do a good job this could lead to you getting a big promotion. You&rsquo;re stoked! You&rsquo;ve been passionate about utility poles since you were a child, and an opportunity like this to dive into a real gnarly utility pole problem and build something robust that you can be proud of will be the highlight of your career so far! You finalize staffing and scheduling of the project, and dive in headfirst.</p>
<h1 id="the-project">The Project</h1>
<p>While you want this project to go as smoothly as possible and will do your best to limit outages for customers, this process requires some downtime. So, you determine a good time for an outage based on customer patterns, and send letters to all customers who might be impacted well in advance. I received such a letter, and knew that on specific days last September I may be without power within given time windows.</p>
<p>The day of the project kickoff actually gets pushed back a week due to poor weather conditions, but you update the customers about that too, and the day finally comes!</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/at%20work%202.jpg#center"
         alt="Project Kickoff: the optimistic meal"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Project Kickoff: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rxJHBewFYos" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >the optimistic meal</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The milestones are flying by perfectly and smoothly. You easily get the new pole installed next to the old one, and after allowing a few days for it to settle (is that how cement works? You tell me, you&rsquo;re the engineer!) you begin migrating wires to the new pole in earnest. Oh man, this new pole is incredible! It&rsquo;s taller than the old one, it&rsquo;s better constructed, it hasn&rsquo;t been beaten down by years of weather. You wish your job always involved working with poles this nice. You tell your boss you&rsquo;re having the time of your life, and they&rsquo;re singing your praises all the way up the org chart. Life is good.</p>
<p>You decide that the smoothest migration path in this case is to move the wires over to the new pole as is, instead of refactoring as you move. This is the least risky approach, and has the least downtime. Besides, once you&rsquo;re over to the new pole and the old pole is gone, life is going to be so much easier: you&rsquo;re going to have more room to operate, and you won&rsquo;t have to deal with all the baggage of the old pole while you focus on finishing the utility pole of your dreams.</p>
<p>You also decide to move the highest risk wires first, because they&rsquo;re the ones that you absolutely need to move to mitigate the business risk. <em>Technically</em>, about 2/3 of these wires would be fine if they stayed on the old pole, so you can wait to move them while you move the higher risk ones.</p>
<p>After a few days, you&rsquo;ve gotten the high risk third of the wires moved over to the new pole. You verify that the entire system is operational, and it&rsquo;s working perfectly! You let out a sigh of relief: you&rsquo;ve completed the hardest parts of this migration. All that&rsquo;s left now is moving the lower risk wires, removing the old pole, and finally getting into that awesome refactor of the new pole that you&rsquo;ve been excited about this whole time.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/after.jpg#center"
         alt="Middle of Project: doesn&amp;rsquo;t look great, but it&amp;rsquo;s a work in progress and actually functions ok temporarily."/> <figcaption>
            <p>Middle of Project: doesn&rsquo;t look great, but it&rsquo;s a work in progress and actually functions ok temporarily.</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>You let your manager know what your team has accomplished already and how smoothly it&rsquo;s gone. Your project is well ahead of schedule, but it&rsquo;s the end of the quarter at PG&amp;E and your manager is looking for some good news to share with their bosses. They proudly report at the big End of Quarter Leadership Roundtable that all of the high risk work on your project is complete, and that you&rsquo;re about to kickoff the cleanup and refactoring phases of the project.</p>
<h1 id="deprioritized">Deprioritized</h1>
<p>The next day, your manager schedules a meeting with you. The mood is tense, and they inform you that unfortunately your project has been deprioritized, effective immediately. What, how? It&rsquo;s not done! Your manager tells you that while they understand how great the cleanup and refactor was going to be, you&rsquo;ve reached the point of the project that technically meets the Definition of Done in your initial proposal. The highest risk wires have been moved to the new utility pole and no longer pose significant risk. Also, the company unfortunately has had to reprioritize their focus on <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/pge-to-pay-55-million-for-two-massive-california-wildfires" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >putting out literal fires</a> and doesn&rsquo;t have the budget right now for &ldquo;unnecessary refactors.&rdquo;</p>
<p>You&rsquo;re really bummed out at this news. This project was just starting to get really interesting! Also, you take pride in the quality of your work, and to abandon this project as is, with TWO poles in the ground and wires on both, gives you a deep sense of shame.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/after.jpg#center"
         alt="Project Completion: Terrible. Just downright dogshit of a pole."/> <figcaption>
            <p>Project Completion: Terrible. <a href="https://twitter.com/spacetwinks/status/965428890830344193" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Just downright dogshit of a pole</a>.</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="post-mortem">Post Mortem</h1>
<p>After a few days of sulking, you begin to reflect more on the situation. Leadership <em>is</em> right. The pole no longer poses a risk, and there are much higher priority issues that need to be addressed. The refactor you had been planning had the potential to be great, but not in a way that really helped the business. You swallow your pride and start to think about your next moves. You still did a good job on this project: you proposed a change to limit business risk, and implemented a solution ahead of schedule. The fact that it looks like it was built by a <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg14619750-500-spiders-on-speed-get-weaving/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >spider on benzedrine</a> doesn&rsquo;t actually matter or show up on any sorts of graphs or metrics that the organization sees. You switch your focus to helping your manager communicate how successful the project was, although they&rsquo;ve informed you that since you didn&rsquo;t get to that technically impressive refactor, your promotion is probably going to have to be pushed back a couple of quarters. At the end of it all, you don&rsquo;t get a promotion but you get a solid performance review, and your manager thanks you privately for being a good team player.</p>
<h1 id="whats-next">What&rsquo;s Next?</h1>
<p>You try to think about what your next move should be. Leadership appears to be singularly focused on an exciting prototype that they&rsquo;ve been testing out to trim trees, a <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2022-03-02/pge-helicopter-saw-bay-area-park-safety-violations" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >&ldquo;heli-saw&rdquo;</a> comprised of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=actkcr-KGpI" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >eight chainsaw blades suspended from a helicopter</a>. They&rsquo;ve got a working prototype, but are looking to hand off to an infrastructure engineer like you to conduct a safety audit and productionalize it. You know that jumping on this project could be good for your career, but your true passion and expertise is in utility poles, and something about dangling chainsaws from helicopters close to power lines just seems a little risky to you.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/helisaw.png#center"
         alt="Fuck everything, we&amp;rsquo;re doing five eight blades"/> <figcaption>
            <p><a href="https://www.theonion.com/fuck-everything-were-doing-five-blades-1819584036" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Fuck everything, we&rsquo;re doing <del>five</del> eight blades</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Can&rsquo;t you just keep working on utility poles? There&rsquo;s still a lot of good work there, but unfortunately your project was deemed so successful and repeatable that you&rsquo;ve started to see double utility poles all over town. You drive over to check on your pole and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BONhk-hbiXk" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >reflect</a>. The person who lives in the house next to your pole sees your PG&amp;E uniform and comes out to talk to you. He tells you that you put the new pole so close to his driveway that he can barely get out of his garage anymore. You want to apologize to him and explain the situation, and tell him it wasn&rsquo;t supposed to be like this. The refactor was going to include alterations to the sidewalk to give him a wider driveway on the other side of the pole. Plus, he was going to be living near the greatest god-damn utility pole in the history of humankind! That pole was going to be so good you might try to figure out if you could be buried under it when you die. But you realize that none of this story changes his situation, and that in this moment you are simply a representative of PG&amp;E to him. You apologize for the inconvenience, tell him <a href="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/EoXRIS9XMAIcRsb?format=jpg&amp;name=900x900" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >we&rsquo;re all trying to find the guy who did this</a>, and promise to report the issue to your manager and put fixing his driveway right at the top of the backlog. He thanks you and goes inside. You get back in your car, knowing his driveway is going to be like this forever.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/repeatable%20process.jpg#center"
         alt="Copycat double poles, now with new innovations like &amp;ldquo;not on the ground, actually.&amp;rdquo;"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Copycat double poles, now with new innovations like &ldquo;not on the ground, actually.&rdquo;</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Distraught, you consider leaving PG&amp;E. They&rsquo;re going through a lot of problems right now, and there are <a href="https://calmatters.org/politics/2020/02/what-happens-if-california-takes-over-pge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >rumors of a takeover</a> by a huge bureaucracy <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >known for its inefficiencies and mismanagement</a>. You&rsquo;re worried that a takeover would cause for a really disruptive couple of years. Also, <a href="https://twitter.com/arimont/status/1022844075903463424" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >the leader</a> doesn&rsquo;t seem to know much about utility companies, and seems to spend most of his time with celebrities and powerful people outside of his industry when he should probably be focused on governing. Also, even though everything he says and does is ostensibly liberal, something about him <em>really</em> makes you feel like he&rsquo;s a Republican.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/newsom%20with%20celebs.jpg#center"
         alt="Governor Gavin Newsom hanging with celebrities instead of working"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Governor Gavin Newsom hanging with celebrities instead of working</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Still, you mostly like your job and love your team. A bunch of new graduates just joined, and they&rsquo;re really excited about utility pole work, just like you used to be! Their energy is contagious. You&rsquo;ve been mentoring them as they do their own utility pole projects, and you end up finding it even more rewarding than working on utility poles directly. You encourage them to do refactoring and cleanup work continuously throughout the project, so that even if it&rsquo;s cut short they&rsquo;ll have improved the situation rather than making it worse. They argue that that&rsquo;s a less efficient way to do the work, but you smile and tell them your story and assure them <a href="https://ih1.redbubble.net/image.1922178116.0850/st,small,507x507-pad,600x600,f8f8f8.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >they&rsquo;ll thank you later</a>.</p>
<p>This is all speculation, of course! I don&rsquo;t know anything about PG&amp;E or utility poles or how infrastructure work like this actually happens. I write software.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unordered List 03-12-2023</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/ul-03-12-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 15:20:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://drew.shoes/posts/ul-03-12-2023/</guid><description>Inspired by my friend Brook&amp;rsquo;s excellent weekly newsletters, here&amp;rsquo;s an unordered list of some things I&amp;rsquo;ve come across lately.
Did The weather in the Bay Area has been rough for the past few weeks, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t been out too much. Part of the joy of living in California is that you kind of give up on fighting the weather. If the weather sucks, just stay inside until it changes, it usually won&amp;rsquo;t be long.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by my friend Brook&rsquo;s <a href="https://buttondown.email/brookshelley" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >excellent weekly newsletters</a>, here&rsquo;s an unordered list of some things I&rsquo;ve come across lately.</p>
<h1 id="did">Did</h1>
<p>The weather in the Bay Area has been rough for the past few weeks, so I haven&rsquo;t been out too much. Part of the joy of living in California is that you kind of give up on fighting the weather. If the weather sucks, just stay inside until it changes, it usually won&rsquo;t be long. This is the maybe worst non-fire-related block of weather I&rsquo;ve experienced since I&rsquo;ve lived in San Francisco, and I finally hit my breaking point this weekend on the &ldquo;wait it out&rdquo; strategy. I got out the limited rain appropriate gear I have, and went for some hikes in the pouring rain. It was glorious, and I now know that I can walk to a peak of Twin Peaks in about 20 minutes from the apartment I recently moved to. I feel invigorated and refreshed, and no longer down in the dumps about the weather. I mean, it&rsquo;s just wet, it&rsquo;s not cold! Today I tried to time my walk with maximum rain, and although I didn&rsquo;t time it perfectly it felt freeing to aim for it. Watching a rainstorm come in from the top of a hill is right up there with watching a brilliant sunset imo.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m also really going through a ramen phase, getting <a href="https://www.marufukuramen.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Marufuku Ramen</a> every time the dreary weather gets to me. Marufuku delivers everything in separate containers, so it delivers very well and reheats wonderfully. I&rsquo;ve started ordering two every time I order so I can have another one the next day.</p>
<h1 id="watched">Watched</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Thomas Flight on Uncut Gems. I have a love/hate relationship with film criticism youtube, but <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7GYmbBH6YT4" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >this video</a> by Thomas Flight on the editing of Uncut Gems to create a sense of anxiety was right up my alley.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7GYmbBH6YT4" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.metafilter.com/198306/2008-Roofball-World-Championships" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >2008 Roofball World Championships</a>. This video is a real nostalgic slice of suburban Americana. I didn&rsquo;t play &ldquo;regulation&rdquo; roofball growing up, but &ldquo;throw a ball on the roof and then try to catch it when it comes back down&rdquo; is definitely something I spent hours doing with friends. Loved the deadpan commentary, the of-the-era &ldquo;iPood&rdquo; parody T-shirt, and the live &ldquo;shame cam&rdquo; in the house for your walk of shame when you throw the ball over the roof.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sSfWL1pPfw0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Jerry Seinfeld in Pulp Fiction Deep Fake. the laugh track on this really did it for me.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/S1MBVXkQbWU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In TV, lately I&rsquo;ve been watching and enjoying:</p>
<ul>
<li>Party Down (old and new)</li>
<li>Drive To Survive (newest season)</li>
<li>Monk (holds up really well! They&rsquo;re all on Peacock)</li>
<li>Poker Face</li>
<li>Survivor (newest season)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>In Movies, you can check my <a href="https://letterboxd.com/dtschust/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >letterboxd</a> but lately I really enjoyed:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Worst Person in the World</li>
<li>Knock at the Cabin</li>
<li>The Menu</li>
<li>Magic Mike XXL (a rewatch. It&rsquo;s tons better than the new one, and the gas station sequence is one of the greatest things I&rsquo;ve ever seen in a theater. If you haven&rsquo;t seen the scene, the only context you need is that Joe Manganiello has lost his mojo and has decided he needs to make this cashier smile or he&rsquo;ll stop dancing forever. Also, they&rsquo;re all on molly.)

	<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
	  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HtjhTj7dXXA" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
	</div>
</li>
<li>M3gan</li>
<li>Triangle of Sadness</li>
<li>Nope</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="read">Read</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Brent Simmons <a href="https://inessential.com/2023/02/20/on_not_taking_money_for_netnewswire" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >On Not Taking Money for NetNewsWire</a>. Major &ldquo;that&rsquo;s fine for Merlin&rdquo; energy on this one, I don&rsquo;t think these arguments apply for most folks trying to make software for people to use (he makes this explicit in the post). Still, it was an interesting perspective for why Brent specifically doesn&rsquo;t take money for NetNewsWire.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Robin Sloan&rsquo;s newsletter post <a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/newsletters/ring-got-good/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >How the Ring Got Good</a> shared his thoughts from reading The History of The Lord of the Rings and his surprise about how much Tolkien had to revise and modify his work before it became the classic we know today. The actual book sounds very interesting, but this article whet my appetite and had some great examples without the time investment of reading the whole thing. I never made it all the way through the Silmarillion, there&rsquo;s no way I&rsquo;m getting through this.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Clive Thompson&rsquo;s <a href="https://clivethompson.medium.com/the-power-of-indulging-your-weird-offbeat-obsessions-77c12f10e69f" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >The Power of Indulging Your Weird, Offbeat Obsessions</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Steve Blank&rsquo;s <a href="https://steveblank.com/2009/12/21/the-elves-leave-middle-earth-%e2%80%93-soda%e2%80%99s-are-no-longer-free/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >The Elves Leave Middle Earth – Sodas Are No Longer Free</a>. This post has a lot that rubs me the wrong way in terms of the deification of the &ldquo;elder software engineer&rdquo;, but nonetheless was a thought-provoking anecdote about how small cultural changes at a company can directly cause rapid and significant declines.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Charlie Jane Anders&rsquo; <a href="https://buttondown.email/charliejane/archive/jk-rowling-and-separating-the-art-from-the-artist/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >J.K. Rowling and &ldquo;Separating the Art from the Artist&rdquo;</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>San Francisco Chronicle&rsquo;s story on <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/oursf/article/sky-tram-gondola-sf-17811209.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >our doomed Ocean Beach Gondola in the 1950&rsquo;s</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Even though I dislike long distance running, Winnie Lim&rsquo;s <a href="https://winnielim.org/journal/more-of-the-same/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >more of the same</a> post about the flow state and mental health benefits of endurance exercise really resonated with me. This experience maps well to when I was cycling regularly. I&rsquo;ve gotta get back into that.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sophie Koonin&rsquo;s <a href="https://localghost.dev/blog/painting-the-whole-beetle-an-adventure-in-learning-to-learn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Painting the whole beetle: an adventure in learning to learn</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://pages.gseis.ucla.edu/faculty/agre/how-to-help.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >How to help someone use a computer</a> by Phil Agre.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.polygon.com/videos/23597903/taking-notes-makes-gaming-more-fun-fez-golden-idol-obra-dinn" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Taking notes makes gaming more fun</a> by Clayton Ashley at Polygon. I&rsquo;d recommend reading the post over watching the video, the video has a bit too much &ldquo;Content&rdquo; energy.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Alex Kladov&rsquo;s <a href="https://matklad.github.io/2023/02/12/a-love-letter-to-deno.html#3-Deno" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >&lt;3 Deno</a> on what he likes about <code>deno</code>, an alternative runtime to <code>node</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Jon Udell&rsquo;s <a href="https://blog.jonudell.net/2023/01/19/of-course-the-attention-economy-is-threatened-by-the-fediverse/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Of course the attention economy is threatened by the Fediverse</a>, in particular:</p>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>But gradually I came to see that there was a sweet spot, somewhere between (let’s say) 200 and 15,000 followers, where it was possible to enjoy the kinds of pleasant and stimulating interaction that I’d first experienced in web forums and the blogosophere.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="played">Played</h1>
<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;ve really been enjoying playing <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1294420/Rollerdrome" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Rollerdrome</a> on my Steam Deck. It&rsquo;s sort of a Tony Hawk Pro Skater shooter, with bullet time and a really cool art style. A great single player game! I&rsquo;ve 100%-ed the main game, and am now working through the post game higher difficulty modes.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wXeOF_8ROlE" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="listened">Listened</h1>
<ul>
<li>John Gruber&rsquo;s <a href="https://daringfireball.net/thetalkshow/2023/03/11/ep-370" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >The Talk Show podcast episode</a> with Jason Kottke on the 25th anniversary of Kottke.org. I&rsquo;m no longer a regular reader or listener of Gruber or Kottke, but this nostalgia trip through the history of blogging and the rise of paywalls/death of APIs was a fun listen in the current collapse of Twitter climate. I&rsquo;m not a 2Xer generally but this bad boy is over 3 hours and &hellip; works very well at 2X speed.</li>
<li>I wrote most of this post listening to the new-ish albums from <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/0HiZ8fNXwJOQcrf5iflrdz?si=JymDWp-yQHSgrPBB7EFrXA" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Miley Cyrus</a> and <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/3l2Gi0hMjZV2uvKoWlFkoQ?si=_x4wyn4BShG44WRt7WjZSg" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Carly Rae Jepsen</a>. They&rsquo;re great.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="computered">Computered</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://arc.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Arc Browser</a>. I&rsquo;m very hesitant to switch browsers, but last year I tried out Vivaldi after reading <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/vivaldi-4-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >an article in Wired</a> (use <a href="https://12ft.io/proxy?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2Fstory%2Fvivaldi-4-2021%2F" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >12ft.io</a> to sidestep the paywall). I didn&rsquo;t end up sticking with Vivaldi, but I did like the idea of vertical tabs. Anyway, I finally gave Arc Browser a try and have really been enjoying it. There&rsquo;s a lot of features I don&rsquo;t currently have any interest in, but the command palette, vertical tabs, and the shockingly game changing <a href="https://bootcamp.uxdesign.cc/arc-browsers-peek-simplified-way-of-interacting-with-tabs-6d1a17d4dab1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >&ldquo;Peek&rdquo; feature</a> have caused me to stick with it for the last couple weeks. I still do development in Chrome, and I intellectually miss the incredible performance and battery life wins of Safari, but I&rsquo;ve got a fast computer that&rsquo;s always plugged in so I&rsquo;m fine taking the hit right now.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://ia.net/presenter" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >iA Presenter</a>. I recently used iA Presenter, currently in beta, to make a presentation for work and I found it equal parts pleasant and maddening. I&rsquo;ve loved and used their excellent <a href="https://ia.net/writer" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >iA Writer</a> for years now, but I don&rsquo;t think this new tool is going to be a good fit for my needs. In the invite email, they explicitly say &ldquo;You probably won’t enjoy iA Presenter that much if you are looking for a Markdown PowerPoint-clone&rdquo;, which turns out is exactly what I want. This tool seems great for anyone who doesn&rsquo;t work in a corporate job that demands slides with bullets of text on them. I understand the designer community disdain for the &ldquo;slide full of bullets&rdquo;, but in my corporate job most people don&rsquo;t come to the presentation and just wanna skim through the slides later anyway. Anyway, if you want a way to easily make aesthetically pleasing slides while mostly working in text, and you don&rsquo;t need the ability to make pixel perfect layout decisions, maybe this is a good tool for you. Just be aware that if people would like a copy of the slides, your only export options are markdown, the ugliest PDF you&rsquo;ve ever seen*, or a 10 megabyte folder containing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>*<em>Update: there&rsquo;s several options to make PDF export better, I like the &ldquo;1 Slide, Borderless&rdquo; option personally. Thanks for <a href="https://fosstodon.org/@FIGBERT/110014371528338371" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >the tip</a> @FIGBERT!</em></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://feedbin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >FeedBin</a>. I&rsquo;ve finally switched to FeedBin in advance of the death of my long used and beloved <a href="https://feedwrangler.net/welcome.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Feed Wrangler</a>. I stuck with Feed Wrangler for a long time mostly because I built my own web app to use as an RSS reader and it was built specifically to Feed Wrangler&rsquo;s API. Now that I&rsquo;ve been forced to switch, I updated my web app to support FeedBin and it&rsquo;s been smooth sailing ever since. I really love FeedBin&rsquo;s newsletter and twitter support. You can give a newsletter a custom feedbin email address and have all of your newsletters in the RSS reader interface, and you can also follow twitter accounts and have those piped in, which is great because twitter hasn&rsquo;t had RSS support for years. I fully expect the twitter integration to break in the next few months because of twitter&rsquo;s current situation, but for now it&rsquo;s been nice.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@fediversereport/109813142639096272" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >StreetPass</a>, a browser extension that will collect mastodon profiles for web sites you visit throughout the day, and let you choose to follow them. What I love about this is that it&rsquo;s powered by the links that <a href="https://docs.joinmastodon.org/user/profile/#verification" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Mastodon checks to verify bio links</a>, so people don&rsquo;t have to be aware of this browser extension to support it. Long live the Open Web and meta tags, baby!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://social.coop/@graue/109719222045865339" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >BikeHopper</a>, an open source directions app for transit and bikes. Google Maps bike directions are pretty ok in San Francisco, but there&rsquo;s definitely room for improvement. I usually start with Google Maps directions and then end up following cyclists on my route who look like they know what they&rsquo;re doing. I frequently end up on a safer and smoother route than the initial one Google recommends. Hopefully this tool helps as well!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The great Darius Kazemi&rsquo;s <a href="https://tinysubversions.com/twitter-archive/make-your-own/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" >got a tool</a> for taking your exported twitter archive and making it accessible and searchable. I&rsquo;ve been a big fan of Darius ever since his incredible deadpan XOXO talk skewering lucky successful tech people who like to advise others on how to mirror their success, as if it&rsquo;s a repeatable process.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l_F9jxsfGCw" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>ok, bye.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>sup</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/sup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 17:41:43 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://drew.shoes/posts/sup/</guid><description>When I was in junior high, my friends and I discovered that a Command Prompt command called net send was enabled on our school network. AIM and similar services were blocked, but if we wanted to send messages to each other we could open up the Command Prompt and type something like:
net send lab2126-24 test and get an alert that looked like: The computer names were predictable, something like lab + room number + computer number, and the computer numbers were physically written on the machines themselves.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was in junior high, my friends and I discovered that a Command Prompt command called <a href="%28https://www.lifewire.com/net-send-2618095%29" >net send</a> was enabled on our school network. AIM and similar services were blocked, but if we wanted to send messages to each other we could open up the Command Prompt and type something like:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-text" data-lang="text"><span style="display:flex;"><span>net send lab2126-24 test
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>and get an alert that looked like:

  <img loading="lazy" src="./images/net%20send%20alert.png" alt="net send alert screenshot" />
</p>
<p>The computer names were predictable, something like lab + room number + computer number, and the computer numbers were physically written on the machines themselves. It was pretty clunky, and there was no scrollback, but it was a fun way to goof off during class by sending each other short messages.</p>
<p>We quickly discovered a few interesting characteristics of <code>net send</code> that could be used for some silliness. For one, the alert dialog that opened up stole keyboard focus and was generally disruptive. You could spam as many <code>net send</code> commands as you wanted and the alerts would just pile up on a user&rsquo;s screen, with no clear way to dismiss them all. We took advantage of this by mashing up and enter as well as writing batch scripts to render our friends&rsquo; computers useless. Eventually a tense truce was called, when we found out that receiving a <code>net send</code> message while playing the hidden copy of Unreal Tournament GOTY we had installed on the school network would temporarily take the player out of the game for just long enough to be killed in a critical moment.</p>
<p>The most creative exploit we came up with for <code>net send</code> was on students (and teachers) who weren&rsquo;t yet aware of the feature. We had the ability to open an official windows alert on anyone&rsquo;s machine, and at a glance it wasn&rsquo;t obvious these messages were coming from another computer on the network. We started sending messages like &ldquo;Critical Error: Please Restart Your Computer Immediately&rdquo; and would watch with glee as our victim sighed deeply before restarting their computer.</p>
<p>The <code>net send</code> joyriding was shortlived, however. Curious about any other avenues of abuse, I looked up the documentation for <code>net send</code> at home one evening and saw that it had wildcard support! Reading the docs, it appeared that if you did <code>net send * MESSAGE</code>, the MESSAGE would be sent to every computer on the entire network. As I did not have a home network to test this on at the time, I anxiously waited until the next day at school to tell my friends.</p>
<p>The next day at lunch, I went to the computer lab and pulled up the documentation online for my friend Eric, and began explaining what I thought it did. As I was explaining that of course we shouldn&rsquo;t try such a thing because we would get in huge trouble if it worked, he ignored me and quickly typed into his machine and submitted the command that would forever live in infamy among our friends:

  <img loading="lazy" src="./images/net%20send%20*%20sup.png" alt="screenshot of windows command prompt with the command: net send * sup" />
</p>
<p>After a very brief moment, Eric&rsquo;s computer received the sup message. I glanced at mine and saw the very same sup message. A terrifying slow pan of our heads across the entire lab confirmed our fears: sup on every screen. <strong>We&rsquo;d gone wall to wall sup!</strong></p>
<p>If you look back at the screenshot of the alert above, there&rsquo;s another detail you might have missed: the alert text contains the name of the computer that sent the message. We were sitting at computer XX in room YYYY while everyone else looked at a message from lab-YYYY-XX. We were seated directly in front of the smoking gun. Like any reasonable 8th graders, we responded by immediately unplugging the computer and sprinting out of the room and down the stairs.</p>
<p>When I got home from school, my younger sister who went to another school in the same district told me and my parents that every machine in her school had received a strange message that day that simply said &ldquo;sup&rdquo;. I held the best poker face my 14 year old self could, which I&rsquo;m sure was not very convincing.</p>
<p>In retrospect, it&rsquo;s fortunate that the <code>net send</code> alert didn&rsquo;t include the username, only the originating machine. I&rsquo;m not sure if there are potentially audit logs that could determine which user sent which message, and now that I&rsquo;m a grownup I know that this was pretty harmless and we wouldn&rsquo;t have gotten in very much trouble anyway.</p>
<p>By the time we got to school the next day, the IT person had disabled <code>net send</code> across the network. We&rsquo;d flown too close to the sun, and I forever learned my lesson: <strong>never read the docs</strong>.</p>
<p>This is my first post on this website, and when trying to think of what to say first this story came back to me, because Eric said everything that needed to be said on that fateful day:</p>
<p align="center">
↓
<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
↓
<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
↓
<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
↓
<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
sup
</p>
<script>
(function () {
  function maybeAlertSup() {
    if ((window.innerHeight + window.pageYOffset) >= document.body.offsetHeight - 100) {
        window.alert("sup");
  	  removeEventListener("scroll", maybeAlertSup)
    }
  }
  addEventListener("scroll", maybeAlertSup);
})();
</script>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>