<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on drew dot shoes</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on drew dot shoes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 21:50:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drew.shoes/posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving the Posts: Adventures in Legacy Infrastructure Migrations</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/moving-the-posts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 21:50:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://drew.shoes/posts/moving-the-posts/</guid><description>I figured I&amp;rsquo;d mix things up a little bit and write a post that has nothing to do with computers or software development.
At my previous apartment in the Richmond neighborhood of San Francisco, there was a utility pole right outside my apartment that was a real eyesore. My pole wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly special, most utility poles in the neighborhood looked like this: wires snaking out in every direction, across the street, tangling through trees, etc.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I figured I&rsquo;d mix things up a little bit and write a post that has nothing to do with computers or software development.</p>
<p>At my previous apartment in the Richmond neighborhood of San Francisco, there was a utility pole right outside my apartment that was a real eyesore. My pole wasn&rsquo;t particularly special, most utility poles in the neighborhood looked like this: wires snaking out in every direction, across the street, tangling through trees, etc. On windy days, two wires that appeared to have simply been cut instead of removed would loudly bang against my windows. On a day without fog (rare), the wires obstructed my very narrow view of the Golden Gate Bridge.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t know enough about how any of this works to know <em>why</em> this utility pole might have been in need of some maintenance, but it certainly didn&rsquo;t give a ton of confidence even at a glance by a layman like myself. Regardless, the company in charge of this pole, <a href="https://www.pge.com/">PG&amp;E</a>, did invest in some maintenance last year, and I&rsquo;d like to imagine what might have happened.</p>
<h1 id="the-proposal">The Proposal</h1>
<p>Let&rsquo;s pretend you are the infrastructure engineer at PG&amp;E who is in charge of this pole. You&rsquo;ve been watching more and more wires get added to this pole over the years, each one increasing the complexity and overall risk of the system. Finally, some change or decay in the system crossed a risk threshold where you now felt the need to advocate for maintenance and improvements. You write a proposal and share it with leadership. The proposal has all the usual things:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Describing the problem and its impact</strong>: You break down what&rsquo;s wrong with the current implementation of this pole, and the risks to the business of not addressing them.</li>
<li><strong>Definition of Done</strong>: You outline what a successful migration is. In this case, a successful migration would be that the new pole is installed, the wires have been attached to it, and the system is still operating smoothly.</li>
<li><strong>The Proposal</strong>: You define the phases and milestones of the project. Obviously there&rsquo;s more detail, but these would be the basic steps:
<ul>
<li>Install a new utility pole next to the existing one.</li>
<li>Migrate existing wires to the new pole.</li>
<li>Refactor the system (either during the migration or afterwards, whichever makes the most sense) to clean up the technical debt that&rsquo;s accumulated over time.</li>
<li>Verify that the migration has been a success.</li>
<li>Remove the old utility pole.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>These sorts of proposals get written at your company all the time, and most of them never get prioritized. For some reason, either due to the quality of your proposal, the potential risk of not fixing the pole, or just sheer luck and timing, your project gets funded! Your manager tells you this project is going to have really high visibility, and that if you do a good job this could lead to you getting a big promotion. You&rsquo;re stoked! You&rsquo;ve been passionate about utility poles since you were a child, and an opportunity like this to dive into a real gnarly utility pole problem and build something robust that you can be proud of will be the highlight of your career so far! You finalize staffing and scheduling of the project, and dive in headfirst.</p>
<h1 id="the-project">The Project</h1>
<p>While you want this project to go as smoothly as possible and will do your best to limit outages for customers, this process requires some downtime. So, you determine a good time for an outage based on customer patterns, and send letters to all customers who might be impacted well in advance. I received such a letter, and knew that on specific days last September I may be without power within given time windows.</p>
<p>The day of the project kickoff actually gets pushed back a week due to poor weather conditions, but you update the customers about that too, and the day finally comes!</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/at%20work%202.jpg#center"
         alt="Project Kickoff: the optimistic meal"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Project Kickoff: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rxJHBewFYos">the optimistic meal</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The milestones are flying by perfectly and smoothly. You easily get the new pole installed next to the old one, and after allowing a few days for it to settle (is that how cement works? You tell me, you&rsquo;re the engineer!) you begin migrating wires to the new pole in earnest. Oh man, this new pole is incredible! It&rsquo;s taller than the old one, it&rsquo;s better constructed, it hasn&rsquo;t been beaten down by years of weather. You wish your job always involved working with poles this nice. You tell your boss you&rsquo;re having the time of your life, and they&rsquo;re singing your praises all the way up the org chart. Life is good.</p>
<p>You decide that the smoothest migration path in this case is to move the wires over to the new pole as is, instead of refactoring as you move. This is the least risky approach, and has the least downtime. Besides, once you&rsquo;re over to the new pole and the old pole is gone, life is going to be so much easier: you&rsquo;re going to have more room to operate, and you won&rsquo;t have to deal with all the baggage of the old pole while you focus on finishing the utility pole of your dreams.</p>
<p>You also decide to move the highest risk wires first, because they&rsquo;re the ones that you absolutely need to move to mitigate the business risk. <em>Technically</em>, about 2/3 of these wires would be fine if they stayed on the old pole, so you can wait to move them while you move the higher risk ones.</p>
<p>After a few days, you&rsquo;ve gotten the high risk third of the wires moved over to the new pole. You verify that the entire system is operational, and it&rsquo;s working perfectly! You let out a sigh of relief: you&rsquo;ve completed the hardest parts of this migration. All that&rsquo;s left now is moving the lower risk wires, removing the old pole, and finally getting into that awesome refactor of the new pole that you&rsquo;ve been excited about this whole time.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/after.jpg#center"
         alt="Middle of Project: doesn&amp;rsquo;t look great, but it&amp;rsquo;s a work in progress and actually functions ok temporarily."/> <figcaption>
            <p>Middle of Project: doesn&rsquo;t look great, but it&rsquo;s a work in progress and actually functions ok temporarily.</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>You let your manager know what your team has accomplished already and how smoothly it&rsquo;s gone. Your project is well ahead of schedule, but it&rsquo;s the end of the quarter at PG&amp;E and your manager is looking for some good news to share with their bosses. They proudly report at the big End of Quarter Leadership Roundtable that all of the high risk work on your project is complete, and that you&rsquo;re about to kickoff the cleanup and refactoring phases of the project.</p>
<h1 id="deprioritized">Deprioritized</h1>
<p>The next day, your manager schedules a meeting with you. The mood is tense, and they inform you that unfortunately your project has been deprioritized, effective immediately. What, how? It&rsquo;s not done! Your manager tells you that while they understand how great the cleanup and refactor was going to be, you&rsquo;ve reached the point of the project that technically meets the Definition of Done in your initial proposal. The highest risk wires have been moved to the new utility pole and no longer pose significant risk. Also, the company unfortunately has had to reprioritize their focus on <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/pge-to-pay-55-million-for-two-massive-california-wildfires">putting out literal fires</a> and doesn&rsquo;t have the budget right now for &ldquo;unnecessary refactors.&rdquo;</p>
<p>You&rsquo;re really bummed out at this news. This project was just starting to get really interesting! Also, you take pride in the quality of your work, and to abandon this project as is, with TWO poles in the ground and wires on both, gives you a deep sense of shame.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/after.jpg#center"
         alt="Project Completion: Terrible. Just downright dogshit of a pole."/> <figcaption>
            <p>Project Completion: Terrible. <a href="https://twitter.com/spacetwinks/status/965428890830344193">Just downright dogshit of a pole</a>.</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="post-mortem">Post Mortem</h1>
<p>After a few days of sulking, you begin to reflect more on the situation. Leadership <em>is</em> right. The pole no longer poses a risk, and there are much higher priority issues that need to be addressed. The refactor you had been planning had the potential to be great, but not in a way that really helped the business. You swallow your pride and start to think about your next moves. You still did a good job on this project: you proposed a change to limit business risk, and implemented a solution ahead of schedule. The fact that it looks like it was built by a <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg14619750-500-spiders-on-speed-get-weaving/">spider on benzedrine</a> doesn&rsquo;t actually matter or show up on any sorts of graphs or metrics that the organization sees. You switch your focus to helping your manager communicate how successful the project was, although they&rsquo;ve informed you that since you didn&rsquo;t get to that technically impressive refactor, your promotion is probably going to have to be pushed back a couple of quarters. At the end of it all, you don&rsquo;t get a promotion but you get a solid performance review, and your manager thanks you privately for being a good team player.</p>
<h1 id="whats-next">What&rsquo;s Next?</h1>
<p>You try to think about what your next move should be. Leadership appears to be singularly focused on an exciting prototype that they&rsquo;ve been testing out to trim trees, a <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2022-03-02/pge-helicopter-saw-bay-area-park-safety-violations">&ldquo;heli-saw&rdquo;</a> comprised of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=actkcr-KGpI">eight chainsaw blades suspended from a helicopter</a>. They&rsquo;ve got a working prototype, but are looking to hand off to an infrastructure engineer like you to conduct a safety audit and productionalize it. You know that jumping on this project could be good for your career, but your true passion and expertise is in utility poles, and something about dangling chainsaws from helicopters close to power lines just seems a little risky to you.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/helisaw.png#center"
         alt="Fuck everything, we&amp;rsquo;re doing five eight blades"/> <figcaption>
            <p><a href="https://www.theonion.com/fuck-everything-were-doing-five-blades-1819584036">Fuck everything, we&rsquo;re doing <del>five</del> eight blades</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Can&rsquo;t you just keep working on utility poles? There&rsquo;s still a lot of good work there, but unfortunately your project was deemed so successful and repeatable that you&rsquo;ve started to see double utility poles all over town. You drive over to check on your pole and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BONhk-hbiXk">reflect</a>. The person who lives in the house next to your pole sees your PG&amp;E uniform and comes out to talk to you. He tells you that you put the new pole so close to his driveway that he can barely get out of his garage anymore. You want to apologize to him and explain the situation, and tell him it wasn&rsquo;t supposed to be like this. The refactor was going to include alterations to the sidewalk to give him a wider driveway on the other side of the pole. Plus, he was going to be living near the greatest god-damn utility pole in the history of humankind! That pole was going to be so good you might try to figure out if you could be buried under it when you die. But you realize that none of this story changes his situation, and that in this moment you are simply a representative of PG&amp;E to him. You apologize for the inconvenience, tell him <a href="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/EoXRIS9XMAIcRsb?format=jpg&amp;name=900x900">we&rsquo;re all trying to find the guy who did this</a>, and promise to report the issue to your manager and put fixing his driveway right at the top of the backlog. He thanks you and goes inside. You get back in your car, knowing his driveway is going to be like this forever.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/repeatable%20process.jpg#center"
         alt="Copycat double poles, now with new innovations like &amp;ldquo;not on the ground, actually.&amp;rdquo;"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Copycat double poles, now with new innovations like &ldquo;not on the ground, actually.&rdquo;</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Distraught, you consider leaving PG&amp;E. They&rsquo;re going through a lot of problems right now, and there are <a href="https://calmatters.org/politics/2020/02/what-happens-if-california-takes-over-pge/">rumors of a takeover</a> by a huge bureaucracy <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California">known for its inefficiencies and mismanagement</a>. You&rsquo;re worried that a takeover would cause for a really disruptive couple of years. Also, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gavin_Newsom">the leader</a> doesn&rsquo;t seem to know much about utility companies, and seems to spend most of his time with celebrities and powerful people outside of his industry when he should probably be focused on governing. Also, even though everything he says and does is ostensibly liberal, something about him <em>really</em> makes you feel like he&rsquo;s a Republican.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="images/newsom%20with%20celebs.jpg#center"
         alt="Governor Gavin Newsom hanging with celebrities instead of working"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Governor Gavin Newsom hanging with celebrities instead of working</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Still, you mostly like your job and love your team. A bunch of new graduates just joined, and they&rsquo;re really excited about utility pole work, just like you used to be! Their energy is contagious. You&rsquo;ve been mentoring them as they do their own utility pole projects, and you end up finding it even more rewarding than working on utility poles directly. You encourage them to do refactoring and cleanup work continuously throughout the project, so that even if it&rsquo;s cut short they&rsquo;ll have improved the situation rather than making it worse. They argue that that&rsquo;s a less efficient way to do the work, but you smile and tell them your story and assure them <a href="https://ih1.redbubble.net/image.1922178116.0850/st,small,507x507-pad,600x600,f8f8f8.jpg">they&rsquo;ll thank you later</a>.</p>
<p>This is all speculation, of course! I don&rsquo;t know anything about PG&amp;E or utility poles or how infrastructure work like this actually happens. I write software.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unordered List 03-12-2023</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/ul-03-12-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 15:20:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://drew.shoes/posts/ul-03-12-2023/</guid><description>Inspired by my friend Brook&amp;rsquo;s excellent weekly newsletters, here&amp;rsquo;s an unordered list of some things I&amp;rsquo;ve come across lately.
Did The weather in the Bay Area has been rough for the past few weeks, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t been out too much. Part of the joy of living in California is that you kind of give up on fighting the weather. If the weather sucks, just stay inside until it changes, it usually won&amp;rsquo;t be long.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by my friend Brook&rsquo;s <a href="https://buttondown.email/brookshelley">excellent weekly newsletters</a>, here&rsquo;s an unordered list of some things I&rsquo;ve come across lately.</p>
<h1 id="did">Did</h1>
<p>The weather in the Bay Area has been rough for the past few weeks, so I haven&rsquo;t been out too much. Part of the joy of living in California is that you kind of give up on fighting the weather. If the weather sucks, just stay inside until it changes, it usually won&rsquo;t be long. This is the maybe worst non-fire-related block of weather I&rsquo;ve experienced since I&rsquo;ve lived in San Francisco, and I finally hit my breaking point this weekend on the &ldquo;wait it out&rdquo; strategy. I got out the limited rain appropriate gear I have, and went for some hikes in the pouring rain. It was glorious, and I now know that I can walk to a peak of Twin Peaks in about 20 minutes from the apartment I recently moved to. I feel invigorated and refreshed, and no longer down in the dumps about the weather. I mean, it&rsquo;s just wet, it&rsquo;s not cold! Today I tried to time my walk with maximum rain, and although I didn&rsquo;t time it perfectly it felt freeing to aim for it. Watching a rainstorm come in from the top of a hill is right up there with watching a brilliant sunset imo.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m also really going through a ramen phase, getting <a href="https://www.marufukuramen.com/">Marufuku Ramen</a> every time the dreary weather gets to me. Marufuku delivers everything in separate containers, so it delivers very well and reheats wonderfully. I&rsquo;ve started ordering two every time I order so I can have another one the next day.</p>
<h1 id="watched">Watched</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Thomas Flight on Uncut Gems. I have a love/hate relationship with film criticism youtube, but <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7GYmbBH6YT4">this video</a> by Thomas Flight on the editing of Uncut Gems to create a sense of anxiety was right up my alley.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7GYmbBH6YT4" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.metafilter.com/198306/2008-Roofball-World-Championships">2008 Roofball World Championships</a>. This video is a real nostalgic slice of suburban Americana. I didn&rsquo;t play &ldquo;regulation&rdquo; roofball growing up, but &ldquo;throw a ball on the roof and then try to catch it when it comes back down&rdquo; is definitely something I spent hours doing with friends. Loved the deadpan commentary, the of-the-era &ldquo;iPood&rdquo; parody T-shirt, and the live &ldquo;shame cam&rdquo; in the house for your walk of shame when you throw the ball over the roof.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sSfWL1pPfw0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Jerry Seinfeld in Pulp Fiction Deep Fake. the laugh track on this really did it for me.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/S1MBVXkQbWU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In TV, lately I&rsquo;ve been watching and enjoying:</p>
<ul>
<li>Party Down (old and new)</li>
<li>Drive To Survive (newest season)</li>
<li>Monk (holds up really well! They&rsquo;re all on Peacock)</li>
<li>Poker Face</li>
<li>Survivor (newest season)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>In Movies, you can check my <a href="https://letterboxd.com/dtschust/">letterboxd</a> but lately I really enjoyed:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Worst Person in the World</li>
<li>Knock at the Cabin</li>
<li>The Menu</li>
<li>Magic Mike XXL (a rewatch. It&rsquo;s tons better than the new one, and the gas station sequence is one of the greatest things I&rsquo;ve ever seen in a theater. If you haven&rsquo;t seen the scene, the only context you need is that Joe Manganiello has lost his mojo and has decided he needs to make this cashier smile or he&rsquo;ll stop dancing forever. Also, they&rsquo;re all on molly.)

	<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
	  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HtjhTj7dXXA" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
	</div>
</li>
<li>M3gan</li>
<li>Triangle of Sadness</li>
<li>Nope</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="read">Read</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Brent Simmons <a href="https://inessential.com/2023/02/20/on_not_taking_money_for_netnewswire">On Not Taking Money for NetNewsWire</a>. Major &ldquo;that&rsquo;s fine for Merlin&rdquo; energy on this one, I don&rsquo;t think these arguments apply for most folks trying to make software for people to use (he makes this explicit in the post). Still, it was an interesting perspective for why Brent specifically doesn&rsquo;t take money for NetNewsWire.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Robin Sloan&rsquo;s newsletter post <a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/newsletters/ring-got-good/">How the Ring Got Good</a> shared his thoughts from reading The History of The Lord of the Rings and his surprise about how much Tolkien had to revise and modify his work before it became the classic we know today. The actual book sounds very interesting, but this article whet my appetite and had some great examples without the time investment of reading the whole thing. I never made it all the way through the Silmarillion, there&rsquo;s no way I&rsquo;m getting through this.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Clive Thompson&rsquo;s <a href="https://clivethompson.medium.com/the-power-of-indulging-your-weird-offbeat-obsessions-77c12f10e69f">The Power of Indulging Your Weird, Offbeat Obsessions</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Steve Blank&rsquo;s <a href="https://steveblank.com/2009/12/21/the-elves-leave-middle-earth-%e2%80%93-soda%e2%80%99s-are-no-longer-free/">The Elves Leave Middle Earth – Sodas Are No Longer Free</a>. This post has a lot that rubs me the wrong way in terms of the deification of the &ldquo;elder software engineer&rdquo;, but nonetheless was a thought-provoking anecdote about how small cultural changes at a company can directly cause rapid and significant declines.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Charlie Jane Anders&rsquo; <a href="https://buttondown.email/charliejane/archive/jk-rowling-and-separating-the-art-from-the-artist/">J.K. Rowling and &ldquo;Separating the Art from the Artist&rdquo;</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>San Francisco Chronicle&rsquo;s story on <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/oursf/article/sky-tram-gondola-sf-17811209.php">our doomed Ocean Beach Gondola in the 1950&rsquo;s</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Even though I dislike long distance running, Winnie Lim&rsquo;s <a href="https://winnielim.org/journal/more-of-the-same/">more of the same</a> post about the flow state and mental health benefits of endurance exercise really resonated with me. This experience maps well to when I was cycling regularly. I&rsquo;ve gotta get back into that.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sophie Koonin&rsquo;s <a href="https://localghost.dev/blog/painting-the-whole-beetle-an-adventure-in-learning-to-learn/">Painting the whole beetle: an adventure in learning to learn</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://pages.gseis.ucla.edu/faculty/agre/how-to-help.html">How to help someone use a computer</a> by Phil Agre.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.polygon.com/videos/23597903/taking-notes-makes-gaming-more-fun-fez-golden-idol-obra-dinn">Taking notes makes gaming more fun</a> by Clayton Ashley at Polygon. I&rsquo;d recommend reading the post over watching the video, the video has a bit too much &ldquo;Content&rdquo; energy.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Alex Kladov&rsquo;s <a href="https://matklad.github.io/2023/02/12/a-love-letter-to-deno.html#3-Deno">&lt;3 Deno</a> on what he likes about <code>deno</code>, an alternative runtime to <code>node</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Jon Udell&rsquo;s <a href="https://blog.jonudell.net/2023/01/19/of-course-the-attention-economy-is-threatened-by-the-fediverse/">Of course the attention economy is threatened by the Fediverse</a>, in particular:</p>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>But gradually I came to see that there was a sweet spot, somewhere between (let’s say) 200 and 15,000 followers, where it was possible to enjoy the kinds of pleasant and stimulating interaction that I’d first experienced in web forums and the blogosophere.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="played">Played</h1>
<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;ve really been enjoying playing <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1294420/Rollerdrome">Rollerdrome</a> on my Steam Deck. It&rsquo;s sort of a Tony Hawk Pro Skater shooter, with bullet time and a really cool art style. A great single player game! I&rsquo;ve 100%-ed the main game, and am now working through the post game higher difficulty modes.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wXeOF_8ROlE" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="listened">Listened</h1>
<ul>
<li>John Gruber&rsquo;s <a href="https://daringfireball.net/thetalkshow/2023/03/11/ep-370">The Talk Show podcast episode</a> with Jason Kottke on the 25th anniversary of Kottke.org. I&rsquo;m no longer a regular reader or listener of Gruber or Kottke, but this nostalgia trip through the history of blogging and the rise of paywalls/death of APIs was a fun listen in the current collapse of Twitter climate. I&rsquo;m not a 2Xer generally but this bad boy is over 3 hours and &hellip; works very well at 2X speed.</li>
<li>I wrote most of this post listening to the new-ish albums from <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/0HiZ8fNXwJOQcrf5iflrdz?si=JymDWp-yQHSgrPBB7EFrXA">Miley Cyrus</a> and <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/3l2Gi0hMjZV2uvKoWlFkoQ?si=_x4wyn4BShG44WRt7WjZSg">Carly Rae Jepsen</a>. They&rsquo;re great.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="computered">Computered</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://arc.net/">Arc Browser</a>. I&rsquo;m very hesitant to switch browsers, but last year I tried out Vivaldi after reading <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/vivaldi-4-2021/">an article in Wired</a> (use <a href="https://12ft.io/proxy?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.wired.com%2Fstory%2Fvivaldi-4-2021%2F">12ft.io</a> to sidestep the paywall). I didn&rsquo;t end up sticking with Vivaldi, but I did like the idea of vertical tabs. Anyway, I finally gave Arc Browser a try and have really been enjoying it. There&rsquo;s a lot of features I don&rsquo;t currently have any interest in, but the command palette, vertical tabs, and the shockingly game changing <a href="https://bootcamp.uxdesign.cc/arc-browsers-peek-simplified-way-of-interacting-with-tabs-6d1a17d4dab1">&ldquo;Peek&rdquo; feature</a> have caused me to stick with it for the last couple weeks. I still do development in Chrome, and I intellectually miss the incredible performance and battery life wins of Safari, but I&rsquo;ve got a fast computer that&rsquo;s always plugged in so I&rsquo;m fine taking the hit right now.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://ia.net/presenter">iA Presenter</a>. I recently used iA Presenter, currently in beta, to make a presentation for work and I found it equal parts pleasant and maddening. I&rsquo;ve loved and used their excellent <a href="https://ia.net/writer">iA Writer</a> for years now, but I don&rsquo;t think this new tool is going to be a good fit for my needs. In the invite email, they explicitly say &ldquo;You probably won’t enjoy iA Presenter that much if you are looking for a Markdown PowerPoint-clone&rdquo;, which turns out is exactly what I want. This tool seems great for anyone who doesn&rsquo;t work in a corporate job that demands slides with bullets of text on them. I understand the designer community disdain for the &ldquo;slide full of bullets&rdquo;, but in my corporate job most people don&rsquo;t come to the presentation and just wanna skim through the slides later anyway. Anyway, if you want a way to easily make aesthetically pleasing slides while mostly working in text, and you don&rsquo;t need the ability to make pixel perfect layout decisions, maybe this is a good tool for you. Just be aware that if people would like a copy of the slides, your only export options are markdown, the ugliest PDF you&rsquo;ve ever seen*, or a 10 megabyte folder containing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>*<em>Update: there&rsquo;s several options to make PDF export better, I like the &ldquo;1 Slide, Borderless&rdquo; option personally. Thanks for <a href="https://fosstodon.org/@FIGBERT/110014371528338371">the tip</a> @FIGBERT!</em></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://feedbin.com/">FeedBin</a>. I&rsquo;ve finally switched to FeedBin in advance of the death of my long used and beloved <a href="https://feedwrangler.net/welcome.html">Feed Wrangler</a>. I stuck with Feed Wrangler for a long time mostly because I built my own web app to use as an RSS reader and it was built specifically to Feed Wrangler&rsquo;s API. Now that I&rsquo;ve been forced to switch, I updated my web app to support FeedBin and it&rsquo;s been smooth sailing ever since. I really love FeedBin&rsquo;s newsletter and twitter support. You can give a newsletter a custom feedbin email address and have all of your newsletters in the RSS reader interface, and you can also follow twitter accounts and have those piped in, which is great because twitter hasn&rsquo;t had RSS support for years. I fully expect the twitter integration to break in the next few months because of twitter&rsquo;s current situation, but for now it&rsquo;s been nice.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@fediversereport/109813142639096272">StreetPass</a>, a browser extension that will collect mastodon profiles for web sites you visit throughout the day, and let you choose to follow them. What I love about this is that it&rsquo;s powered by the links that <a href="https://docs.joinmastodon.org/user/profile/#verification">Mastodon checks to verify bio links</a>, so people don&rsquo;t have to be aware of this browser extension to support it. Long live the Open Web and meta tags, baby!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://social.coop/@graue/109719222045865339">BikeHopper</a>, an open source directions app for transit and bikes. Google Maps bike directions are pretty ok in San Francisco, but there&rsquo;s definitely room for improvement. I usually start with Google Maps directions and then end up following cyclists on my route who look like they know what they&rsquo;re doing. I frequently end up on a safer and smoother route than the initial one Google recommends. Hopefully this tool helps as well!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The great Darius Kazemi&rsquo;s <a href="https://tinysubversions.com/twitter-archive/make-your-own/">got a tool</a> for taking your exported twitter archive and making it accessible and searchable. I&rsquo;ve been a big fan of Darius ever since his incredible deadpan XOXO talk skewering lucky successful tech people who like to advise others on how to mirror their success, as if it&rsquo;s a repeatable process.

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l_F9jxsfGCw" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>
</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>ok, bye.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>sup</title><link>https://drew.shoes/posts/sup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 17:41:43 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://drew.shoes/posts/sup/</guid><description>When I was in junior high, my friends and I discovered that a Command Prompt command called net send was enabled on our school network. AIM and similar services were blocked, but if we wanted to send messages to each other we could open up the Command Prompt and type something like:
net send lab2126-24 test and get an alert that looked like: The computer names were predictable, something like lab + room number + computer number, and the computer numbers were physically written on the machines themselves.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was in junior high, my friends and I discovered that a Command Prompt command called <a href="(https://www.lifewire.com/net-send-2618095)">net send</a> was enabled on our school network. AIM and similar services were blocked, but if we wanted to send messages to each other we could open up the Command Prompt and type something like:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-text" data-lang="text"><span style="display:flex;"><span>net send lab2126-24 test
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>and get an alert that looked like:

  <img loading="lazy" src="./images/net%20send%20alert.png" alt="net send alert screenshot" />
</p>
<p>The computer names were predictable, something like lab + room number + computer number, and the computer numbers were physically written on the machines themselves. It was pretty clunky, and there was no scrollback, but it was a fun way to goof off during class by sending each other short messages.</p>
<p>We quickly discovered a few interesting characteristics of <code>net send</code> that could be used for some silliness. For one, the alert dialog that opened up stole keyboard focus and was generally disruptive. You could spam as many <code>net send</code> commands as you wanted and the alerts would just pile up on a user&rsquo;s screen, with no clear way to dismiss them all. We took advantage of this by mashing up and enter as well as writing batch scripts to render our friends&rsquo; computers useless. Eventually a tense truce was called, when we found out that receiving a <code>net send</code> message while playing the hidden copy of Unreal Tournament GOTY we had installed on the school network would temporarily take the player out of the game for just long enough to be killed in a critical moment.</p>
<p>The most creative exploit we came up with for <code>net send</code> was on students (and teachers) who weren&rsquo;t yet aware of the feature. We had the ability to open an official windows alert on anyone&rsquo;s machine, and at a glance it wasn&rsquo;t obvious these messages were coming from another computer on the network. We started sending messages like &ldquo;Critical Error: Please Restart Your Computer Immediately&rdquo; and would watch with glee as our victim sighed deeply before restarting their computer.</p>
<p>The <code>net send</code> joyriding was shortlived, however. Curious about any other avenues of abuse, I looked up the documentation for <code>net send</code> at home one evening and saw that it had wildcard support! Reading the docs, it appeared that if you did <code>net send * MESSAGE</code>, the MESSAGE would be sent to every computer on the entire network. As I did not have a home network to test this on at the time, I anxiously waited until the next day at school to tell my friends.</p>
<p>The next day at lunch, I went to the computer lab and pulled up the documentation online for my friend Eric, and began explaining what I thought it did. As I was explaining that of course we shouldn&rsquo;t try such a thing because we would get in huge trouble if it worked, he ignored me and quickly typed into his machine and submitted the command that would forever live in infamy among our friends:

  <img loading="lazy" src="./images/net%20send%20*%20sup.png" alt="screenshot of windows command prompt with the command: net send * sup" />
</p>
<p>After a very brief moment, Eric&rsquo;s computer received the sup message. I glanced at mine and saw the very same sup message. A terrifying slow pan of our heads across the entire lab confirmed our fears: sup on every screen. <strong>We&rsquo;d gone wall to wall sup!</strong></p>
<p>If you look back at the screenshot of the alert above, there&rsquo;s another detail you might have missed: the alert text contains the name of the computer that sent the message. We were sitting at computer XX in room YYYY while everyone else looked at a message from lab-YYYY-XX. We were seated directly in front of the smoking gun. Like any reasonable 8th graders, we responded by immediately unplugging the computer and sprinting out of the room and down the stairs.</p>
<p>When I got home from school, my younger sister who went to another school in the same district told me and my parents that every machine in her school had received a strange message that day that simply said &ldquo;sup&rdquo;. I held the best poker face my 14 year old self could, which I&rsquo;m sure was not very convincing.</p>
<p>In retrospect, it&rsquo;s fortunate that the <code>net send</code> alert didn&rsquo;t include the username, only the originating machine. I&rsquo;m not sure if there are potentially audit logs that could determine which user sent which message, and now that I&rsquo;m a grownup I know that this was pretty harmless and we wouldn&rsquo;t have gotten in very much trouble anyway.</p>
<p>By the time we got to school the next day, the IT person had disabled <code>net send</code> across the network. We&rsquo;d flown too close to the sun, and I forever learned my lesson: <strong>never read the docs</strong>.</p>
<p>This is my first post on this website, and when trying to think of what to say first this story came back to me, because Eric said everything that needed to be said on that fateful day:</p>
<p align="center">
↓
<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
↓
<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
↓
<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
↓
<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
sup
</p>
<script>
(function () {
  function maybeAlertSup() {
    if ((window.innerHeight + window.pageYOffset) >= document.body.offsetHeight - 100) {
        window.alert("sup");
  	  removeEventListener("scroll", maybeAlertSup)
    }
  }
  addEventListener("scroll", maybeAlertSup);
})();
</script>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>